

CONTACT ME

+357 99 22 85 47

developer.stepanov@gmail.com

github.com/developerStepanov

Paphos, Cyprus

SKILLS

Agile (Scrum), TDD approach

Java 11, Spring (Boot, Security, Data, Cloud), JPA (Hibernate), SQL/NoSQL dbs, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Unit testing, Groovy, Postman testing, Angular 14

Maven, Gradle

Git, Jira, Jenkins

Microservices paradigm

LANGUAGES I SPEAK

English B2 (Upper-Intermediate)

Czech C2 (Proficiency)

Dutch A1 (Beginner)

Russian Native language

MAXIM STEPANOV

JAVA DEVELOPER

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a professional Java developer with 5 years of commercial experience. I am skilled to deliver good designed, well tested and fully functioned code. I have deep understanding of Java ecosystem and related tech stack such as Spring Boot, SQL/NoSQL dbs, Kafka, Docker and many more. I follow test-driven development on a daily basis. I have an experience with mentoring, code-reviewing other team members. I have strong ability to work independently and as part of a team. I am most comfortable and prefer to work in agile team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Java Developer 4Finance (Prague)

August 2021 - Present

- large challenging project consists of 10+ microservices
- refactored some components of a system to improve readability of a code
- implemented new features based on business requirements
- successfully migrated 15 microservices to Kubernetes

Java Developer Innoseti (Kaliningrad)

June 2020 - August 2021

- project had complex solutions based on blockchain technology
- understood, designed and implemented business requirements
- refactored some part of a system to improve readability of code
- wrote set of python scripts when needed

Php Developer

Torch Entertainment (Prague)

January 2018 - April 2020

Java Developer

Fio bank (Prague)

January 2017 - January 2018

Java Developer

Siemens (Brno)

February 2016 - January 2017

EDUCATION

Information technologies

Technical University Ostrava

2014 - 2017 unfinished bachelor degree

Java trainee program **Unicorn Prague**

2015